MYRIAM BENKOUSSA

(860)-830-6591 - benkoussam@outlook.com linkedin.com/in/benkoussam - benkoussam.me - github.com/benkoussam

OBJECTIVE

Software Engineer with a bachelor's degree in Computer Science and four years of experience developing and delivering software solutions in the finance industry. Strong analytical skills and interdisciplinary approach to problem solving, with interest in the applications of computer science to cybersecurity, big data, machine learning, and artificial intelligence.

EDUCATION

Bryn Mawr College, Bryn Mawr, PA

Class of 2019

Haverford College, Haverford, PA via the Bi-College Consortium - B.A. in Computer Science

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer | JP Morgan Chase

August 2019-Present

- Worked in a cross-functional Agile team on the end-to-end containerization of a core rewards processing application that services millions of credit card customers. Migrated the complex legacy application to the private cloud and containerized using Kubernetes, improving scalability and streamlining deployment, as well as modernizing its Java components.
- Modernized and migrated Java web applications to AWS EKS and ECS, conducted performance and chaos engineering tests, and implemented Splunk and DataDog as metrics monitoring solutions.
- Developed, tested, and implemented a microservice to automate onboarding for new rewards redemption options, as well as a solution for a rewards redemption issue that impacted over 50,000 credit card reward customers.
- Collaborated with stakeholders and served as project manager for a team of contractors implementing data purge scripts to meet firmwide data retention policy. Containerized scripts and automated workload execution using Kubernetes-and Control-M.
- Created implementation plans and control procedures for production deployments, provided on-call support, debugged and fixed critical production issues.
- Worked as a part of an Agile team to implement a digital gift card redemption option for Chase credit card rewards. Designed and tested an event-driven solution of microservices with Kafka and Java-based RESTful APIs hosted in private cloud.
- Implemented identity access solutions across various microservices to strengthen security protocols.
- Designed and deployed RESTful APIs to facilitate status and health checks for applications deployed in the private cloud.
- Integrated automated vulnerability detection as a part of the CI/CD pipeline of various applications for enhanced security.

Computer Science Teaching Assistant and Grader | Haverford College

August 2016-May 2019

• Worked as a TA and grader, and hosted office hours for students for the following courses at Haverford College: Principles of Programming Languages, Principles of Computer Organization, Data Structures, Introduction to Computer Science.

Software Engineering Intern | JP Morgan Chase

June 2018-August 2018

• Worked as a part of an Agile team of interns to develop software solutions to migrate the Chase Loyalty Solutions email service from a monolithic application to a self-contained microservice in the private cloud platform.

Digital Scholarship Summer Fellow - Lead Developer | Bryn Mawr College

June 2017-August 2017

• Worked in a team of fellows to design, develop and implement a data visualization project for large datasets of college archives using Python, JavaScript, D3, and jQuery. Normalized and enhanced text and image datasets using R and OpenRefine.

PROJECTS AND RESEARCH

- Undergraduate Thesis completed computer science senior thesis research advised by a Haverford College faculty member. Risk Mitigation in Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Implementation within the Internet of Things (IoT)
- Twitter stock data sentiment analysis using Python
- Fully functional compiler in C++ and HERA assembly language for the Tiger language
- Modeling and simulation of a 16-bit microprocessor based on the HERA assembly language using LogiSim

SKILLS

- Languages: Java, Python, C++, SQL, Javascript/HTML/CSS
- Frameworks and Libraries: Spring/Spring Boot, Spring Batch, React.js, D3, Apache Struts
- Tools: Git, Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, Cloud Foundry, Maven, Jenkins, Postman, Swagger, AWS (EKS, ECS, S3)
- RESTful API proficiency, continuous integration and continuous delivery/deployment (CI/CD) proficiency
- Agile experience, including roles as both Scrum master and developer on development team, Jira proficiency
- PC proficiency (Microsoft Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Publisher)
- Fluent in English, French, Algerian; Competent in Arabic, Latin

MEMBERSHIPS AND CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner - Amazon Web Services Fellow - Rewriting the Code (selective national fellowship for women in technology) Member - Algerian American Association for Science Technology and Entrepreneurship September 2023-Present June 2018-Present January 2024-Present